# Matthew Auld

After five years of working in the non-profit sector, I returned to University in September 2017 to pursue my interest in Computer Science. I have proven myself to be an independent, critical thinker who can work under pressure. I am graduating In June 2020, and looking for an opportunity where I can continue to learn and improve my skills as part of a driven team.

#### **Skills**

- Languages/Tools: C,C++, JavaScript, Python, Java, Rust. Git,
- Databases: MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MongoDB
- Experience with parallel and concurrent software engineering techniques
- Experience with Linux servers and Linux tools
- Working with vendors, project management and internal clients on large IT projects
- Data analysis using SQL, Python Pandas,
- Frameworks: React, lit-elements, MPI, nodejs addons (C/C++)

#### **Education**

2017-PRESENT (GRADUATING JUNE 2020)

# **B.Sc Computer Science (Honours)**/ Carleton University

- Specializing in Cyber Security and Software Engineering A+ course average
- In addition to require courses, took upper year courses in Algebraic Structures Cryptography, Real-Time Systems, Parallel and Concurrent Computing
- Working on honors project involving applications of Attribute Based Encryption in peer-to-peer systems

SEPT 2006 - JUNE 2011

#### B.A Political Science (Honours) / University of Guelph

- Completed a degree in Political Science, specializing in Public Administration and Law
- Completed upper year classes in economics, philosophy and political theory

### **Experience**

JAN 2019 - PRESENT

#### **Teaching Assistant / Carleton University**

- Classes: Introduction to Computer Science II (two semesters), Object Oriented Software Engineering (one semester), Special project (one semester)
- Responsible for running tutorials, holding office hours, marking assignments and tests, and assisting students with major projects
- Spent four months working on a server used to compile and grade student assignments, identified and fixed security flaws and improved user experience

MAR 2018 - DEC 2018 (PART TIME), SUMMER 2018 (FULL TIME)

### Data Analyst / Canadian Red Cross

- Developed and maintained internal migration and donor data cleanup documentation
- Developed scripts to extract, analyze and compile translation tables from Raiser's Edge using SQL and Python, saving huge amount of time in manual review and increasing accuracy
- Troubleshot conversion issues with the Blackbaud Data Conversion Team
- Monitored data consistency, diagnose issues and proactively develop methodologies to improve data quality, allowing for consistant analysis of the effects of donor strewardship stratagies
- Developed and helped to implement a reporting plan to migrate all analytic to new data warehouse and CRM systems

JULY 2016 - AUGUST 2017 (FULL TIME), SEPTEMBER 2017 - MARCH 2018 (PART TIME)

## National Stewardship Coordinator / Canadian Red Cross

- Using Python Pandas, SQL and Pointillist software, performed data analysis to identify opportunities to improve donor retention
- Worked with vendors and internal partners to automate stewardship marketing processes, including welcome emails, surveys, and the fast identification of problems
- Working with Public Affairs, Program, Data, Translation and Design teams, I managed the development and of stewardship material for all Canadian Red Cross stakeholders and donors, including major reports for the 2016 Alberta Fires and 2017 BC Floods

MAY 2013 - JULY 2016

# Community Engagement Associate / Canadian Red Cross

• Worked to engage communities and corporations across Ontario and to assist them in raising funds and awareness during major domestic and international disasters.

### **Volunteer Experience**

# **Disaster Management Responder and Logistics Lead** / Canadian Red Cross

JANUARY 2014 - JAN 2017

- Developed logistics database to track assets and inventory levels
- Standardized warehousing procedures and trained volunteers and implement systems
- Supported the spring flood evacuations in 2014 and 2015, Syrian Response as well as a number of major fires
- Sat on the ERMS working group, developing standard operating procedures for using the ERMS for level 2 responses in Ottawa-Lanark-Renfew
- Deployed to Fort McMurray in June 2016 as Logistics Manager stationed there. Was tasked with implementing all procurement, inventory and asset tracking for the response

### **Awards**

- Dean's List 2017-2018,2018-2019 Carleton University
- Murdoch Maxwell MacOdrum Scholarship 2018-2019, 2019-2020 Carleton University
- Jamie Corbet Memorial Award 2018-2019 Carleton University Awarded annually, on the recommendation of the School of Computer Science, to an outstanding student who is proceeding from one year to another in the School of Computer Science.
- National Service Award 2018 for Disaster Management volunteer work
- National Youth Service Award 2017 for Disaster Management volunteer work